<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Audit - Tag - Trackflaw | Cybersecurity expert</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/audit/</link>
        <description>Audit - Tag - Trackflaw | Cybersecurity expert</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:21:12 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/audit/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Why You Should STOP Using Kali Linux</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/why-should-you-no-longer-use-kali-linux/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 15:21:12 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/why-should-you-no-longer-use-kali-linux/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/pourquoi-vous-ne-devriez-plus-utiliser-kali-linux-/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="exegol-the-best-modern-alternative-to-kali-linux">Exegol: The Best Modern Alternative to Kali Linux</h1>
<h2 id="the-history-of-kali-linux-a-rise-to-power">The History of Kali Linux: A Rise to Power</h2>
<p><strong>Kali Linux</strong> is a <strong>must-have</strong> distribution, widely recognized by professionals in the security field, especially for <strong>pentesters</strong> and <strong>offensive security auditors</strong>.</p>
<p>However, with the emergence of new technologies and lighter alternatives, <strong>should you still use Kali Linux</strong>? In this article, we revisit the evolution of this OS, explore its alternatives, and see how solutions like <strong>Exegol</strong>, based on Docker, are redefining hacking environments.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How penetration tests help ensure GDPR compliance?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/how-does-intrusion-tests-help-guarantee-rgpd-compliance/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:18:54 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/how-does-intrusion-tests-help-guarantee-rgpd-compliance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/comment-les-tests-dintrusion-aident-%c3%a0-garantir-la-conformit%c3%a9-rgpd-/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="penetration-testing-and-gdpr-compliance-the-essentials">Penetration testing and GDPR compliance: the essentials</h1>
<h2 id="a-matter-of-protection">A matter of protection</h2>
<p>As a business leader, it is unlikely that you have never heard the term <strong>GDPR</strong>. Indeed, it has been at the heart of digital concerns for businesses for several years 🛡️.</p>
<p><strong>The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)</strong> imposes strict standards regarding the <strong>protection of personal data</strong> within the European Union.</p>
<p>Since its implementation in <strong>May 2018</strong>, companies have had to take rigorous measures to secure the data <strong>they collect and process</strong>. Among these measures, penetration testing proves to be an <strong>essential tool for ensuring GDPR compliance</strong>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What tools to use for a Penetration Test?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/what-tools-to-use-for-an-intrusion-test/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 11:58:40 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/what-tools-to-use-for-an-intrusion-test/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/quels-outils-utiliser-pour-un-test-dintrusion/logo.en.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-tools-in-the-field-of-penetration-testing">🛠️ Tools in the Field of Penetration Testing</h1>
<h2 id="importance-of-penetration-testing">Importance of Penetration Testing</h2>
<p><strong>Penetration testing</strong>, also known as <strong>pentesting</strong> (or colloquially as penetration testing), is an essential practice for <strong>evaluating the security of an IT system</strong>. It involves simulating real attacks to <strong>identify</strong> and <strong>fix</strong> <strong>vulnerabilities</strong> before actual malicious attackers exploit them.</p>
<p>To conduct a successful penetration test, it&rsquo;s crucial to have the right <strong>tools</strong>. However, navigating the plethora of available tools can be overwhelming.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What budget to provide for its intrusion test</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/what-budget-to-provide-for-its-intrusion-test/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 10:01:20 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/what-budget-to-provide-for-its-intrusion-test/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/quel-budget-pr%c3%a9voir-pour-son-test-intrusion/logo.en.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-how-much-does-a-computer-intrusion-test-cost-in-2024">💰 How much does a computer intrusion test cost in 2024?</h1>
<h2 id="cybersecurity-a-21st-century-issue">Cybersecurity: a 21st-century issue</h2>
<p>In an ever-evolving digital world, <strong>computer intrusion tests</strong> are becoming increasingly crucial for ensuring the security of a company&rsquo;s information systems. 🎯</p>
<p>Whether it&rsquo;s to protect sensitive data or to maintain business operations, <strong>cybersecurity</strong> is at the heart of every organization&rsquo;s concerns.</p>
<p>One of the most frequent questions that companies ask is the <strong>cost of a penetration test in 2024</strong>. This article is here to guide you through the various factors influencing the cost of a penetration test and how to effectively budget for this essential operation.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>XZ Utils: the backdoor shaking the free world and cybersecurity</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/xz-utils-the-backdoor-shaking-the-free-world/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 10:21:17 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/xz-utils-the-backdoor-shaking-the-free-world/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/xz-utils-:-la-backdoor-faisant-trembler-le-monde-libre/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-new-and-scandalous-backdoor-in-xz-utils-on-linux">🕶️ New and scandalous backdoor in XZ Utils on Linux</h1>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>On <strong>March 29, 2024</strong>, a major security flaw was discovered in <code>XZ Utils</code>, a package widely used in popular Linux distributions. This flaw, known as <strong>CVE-2024-3094</strong>, allows attackers to <strong>execute code remotely</strong> on affected systems.</p>
<h2 id="tldr">TL;DR</h2>
<p><strong>CVE-2024-3094</strong> introduces a backdoor into the OpenSSH server, allowing attackers in possession of a <strong>UNIQUE</strong> private key to launch commands before the authentication step.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why do an intrusion test on its WordPress site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/why-do-an-intrusion-test-on-its-wordpress-site/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 10:54:14 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/why-do-an-intrusion-test-on-its-wordpress-site/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/pourquoi-faire-un-test-intrusion-sur-son-site-Wordpress/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="why-a-penetration-test-is-mandatory-for-your-wordpress-site-in-2024">Why a Penetration Test is MANDATORY for Your Wordpress Site in 2024?</h1>
<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p><strong>WordPress</strong>, as one of the <strong>most widely used content management systems (CMS) in the world</strong>, powers a significant portion of websites, ranging from personal blogs to corporate sites.</p>
<p>However, its popularity comes with increased security risks, making penetration testing crucial for safeguarding these sites against cyber attacks.</p>
<p>📈 Some staggering statistics (according to lesmakers.fr):</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>#1</strong> CMS in the world.</li>
<li>Over <strong>62% market share</strong> among CMS.</li>
<li>More than <strong>43% of global websites</strong> use WordPress.</li>
<li><strong>9,000</strong> free themes.</li>
<li><strong>60,000</strong> free active plugins.</li>
</ul>
<br>
<figure><figcaption>
      <h4>More than 62% of sites using a CMS opt for WordPress</h4>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><figcaption>
      <h4>Over 455 million websites worldwide use WordPress.</h4>
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="a-double-edged-sword-of-popularity">A double-edged sword of popularity</h2>
<p><strong>WordPress</strong> is often targeted by attackers due to its widespread use.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>GhostRace: New concern CPU vulnerability</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/ghostrace-new-concern-cpu-vulnerability/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:39:17 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/ghostrace-new-concern-cpu-vulnerability/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/GhostRace-nouvelle-vuln%c3%a9rabilit%c3%a9-CPU-pr%c3%a9occupante/logo.en.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-ghostrace-specter-v20">👻 GhostRace: Specter v2.0?</h1>
<h2 id="tldr">TL;DR</h2>
<p>A new class of <strong>speculative execution</strong> vulnerabilities, named <strong>GhostRace</strong>, has been discovered in March 2024. This attack is particularly dangerous as it can be used to exploit a wide array of software, including web browsers, operating systems, and critical applications.</p>
<h2 id="the-theory">The Theory</h2>
<p>But how does the <strong>GhostRace</strong> attack work? 🤔</p>
<p>The <strong>GhostRace</strong> attack (<a href="https://www.cve.org/CVERecord?id=CVE-2024-2193" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">CVE-2024-2193</a>) exploits flaws in synchronization primitives, which are software tools used to coordinate the execution of multiple processes or threads.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Compromise Jenkins reading files CVE-2024-23897</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/compromise-jenkins-reading-files-cve-2024-23897/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 11:47:21 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/compromise-jenkins-reading-files-cve-2024-23897/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/compromettre-jenkins-lecture-fichiers-CVE-2024-23897/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-from-a-minor-verbose-error-to-full-compromise">💣 From a minor verbose error to full compromise</h1>
<h2 id="the-origin">The origin</h2>
<p>On <strong>January 25, 2024</strong>, researchers from Sonar published 2 vulnerabilities related to the leader in open-source continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) software: <strong>Jenkins</strong>.</p>
<p>Jenkins plays a central role in <strong>automating software development processes</strong> for a large part of the industry, holding about <strong>44% market share in 2023</strong>. The potential impact of these vulnerabilities is therefore <strong>significant</strong>.</p>
<p>The most concerning flaw, identified as <strong>CVE-2024-23897</strong>, allows unauthenticated attackers to read limited data from arbitrary files and &ldquo;read-only&rdquo; authorized attackers to access an entire file on the Jenkins server.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Which approach to choose for conducting a penetration test?</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/approach-penetration-test/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 10:39:40 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/approach-penetration-test/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/quelle-d%c3%a9marche-test-intrusion/logo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="-how-to-choose-the-right-approach-for-conducting-a-penetration-test">🤔 How to choose the right approach for conducting a penetration test?</h1>
<h2 id="black-box-gray-box-white-box">Black Box, Gray Box, White Box?</h2>
<p>In the constantly evolving world of cybersecurity, where cyberattacks are becoming increasingly sophisticated, conducting penetration tests has become a necessity for businesses concerned about protecting their IT systems and sensitive data.</p>
<p>These tests, often referred to as black box, gray box, and white box tests, are crucial components of any robust IT security strategy. Each type of test offers a unique approach to assessing information system security and identifying potential vulnerabilities that could be exploited by cyber attackers.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
